<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A True narrative of the confession and execution of several notorious malefactors at Tyburn on Wednesday April the 16th 1684 viz. Charles Close, Bernard Trevers, Hugh Kelly, Katherine Smith, and Mary Corbet who was burnt at Tyburn for high-treason.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1684</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 9 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A63562</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing T2778</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R27019</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">09618932</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 09618932</idno>
            <idno type="VID">43825</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A63562)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 43825)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1344:5)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A True narrative of the confession and execution of several notorious malefactors at Tyburn on Wednesday April the 16th 1684 viz. Charles Close, Bernard Trevers, Hugh Kelly, Katherine Smith, and Mary Corbet who was burnt at Tyburn for high-treason.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>4 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by E. Mallet,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1684.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Harvard University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Executions and executioners --  England.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:43825:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 1 -->
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:43825:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 1 -->
            <head>A TRUE NARRATIVE OF THE CONFESSION AND EXECUTION of ſeveral Notorious Malefactors AT TYBURN, On <date>VVedneſday April the 16th. 1684.</date>
            </head>
            <head type="sub">Viz.
<list>
                  <item>Charles Cloſe,</item>
                  <item>B<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>rnerd Trevers</item>
                  <item>Hugh Kelly,</item>
                  <item>Katherine Smith.</item>
                  <item>and <hi>Mary Corbet,</hi> who was Burnt at <hi>Tyburn</hi> for <hi>High-Treaſon.</hi>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </head>
            <p>THeſe Malefactors, with three more, were Tryed and Condemned at the laſt Seſſions at the <hi>Old-B<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ily,</hi> of which two of them, by his Majeſties great Favor were Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preived, and the other, <hi>Jane Robinſon,</hi> being found quick with Child by a <hi>Jury</hi> of Women impannel'd for that En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiry, was reſpited till her Delivery.</p>
            <p>I ſhall firſt give you a True Account, of the ſeveral Crimes, for which each perſon ſuffered, and then a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation of the Behaviour of them, from the time of their Sentence, to that of Execution.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Charles Cloſe</hi> was an old Offender, and one of thoſe Rogues, who about two years ago, Rob'd Mr. <hi>Croom</hi> an Ale-houſe-keeper, near <hi>Soho Fields,</hi> which was thus, he and two more of his Companions went in to drink, and af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter they had ſtay'd ſometime, and found an Opportunity ſit for their purpoſe; There being no other Company in the
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:43825:2"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 2 -->houſe they ſent down the Maſter for another Tankard of Drink and one of them followed him down Stairs, and of a ſudden knock'd him down; the other coming in to his Aſſiſtance, they us'd him very Barbarouſly, and afterwards rob'd the houſe of a very conſiderable ſum in Monys and Place, and made their Eſcape. But Juſtice which never ſuffers ſuch heinous crimes to go unpuniſhed, at laſt over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>took this Offe<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>der in the Commiſſi<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>n of a ſecond Robbery, with <hi>Bernard Trevers</hi> and <hi>Hugh Ke<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ly,</hi> who were all In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicted for Robbing the houſe of <hi>John Shutleworth,</hi> an <hi>Inn</hi>-keeper at <hi>Wood-Green</hi> in the Pariſh of <hi>Tatenham,</hi> and take<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing away, in Plate and Mony, to the value of two hundred and fifty pounds, they laid their deſign with a great deal of cunning, by firſt going to drink as of they had been paſſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing forward towards <hi>Hornſey.</hi> The <hi>Inn</hi>-keeper ſeeing th<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>m in the habits of Gentlemen, <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ok them for ſuch, and made much of them, thinking he had got good Gueſts, and offered them a Lodging if they would ſtay all Night, when it was dark <hi>Bernard Trevers</hi> let in ſeveral others, who a<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſted them to bind the Family and rob the houſe. <hi>Hugh Kelly</hi> was taken at <hi>Portſmouth</hi> and part of the Plate found with him <hi>Bernard Trevers</hi> was taken about <hi>Charing-Croſs,</hi> and either was, or went in the habit of a Grana<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deer. Theſe three confeſſed upon their Araignment that they were Guilty of Felony and Robbery, but not of bre<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king the houſe: however it being proved that <hi>Trevers</hi> un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bolted a back door to let in the reſt of his Companions, they were all three found Guilty of Felony and Burglary. <hi>Mary Kelly,</hi> the pretended Wife of <hi>Hugh Kelly</hi> was Indi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted as Acceſſary for comforting, aiding, and harbouring them after the Robbery was committed, and a Gold Ring which was part of the Goods ſtole found upon her, but was acquitred</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Katherine Smith,</hi> alias <hi>Sandimore</hi> was a perſon very well known amongſt the Pick-pockets by the Name of <hi>Yorkſhire Kate,</hi> and was Indicted for ſtealing handkerchief and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Linen, the Goods <hi>of Thomas Williams,</hi> and <hi>found</hi> Guilty <hi>of</hi> Felony and Burglary, ſhe had been and Incorri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ble Offender, whom no Acts <hi>of</hi> Clemency could oblige to
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:43825:2"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 2 -->an honeſt Life, ſhe having formerly Six or Seven times, received the mercy of the Bench.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Mary Corbet</hi> was formerly a Broker, and by her conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nual Crimes had rendred her ſelf Obnoxious to the Law, but Mercy ſtill prevented that puniſhment which ſhe had ſo often deſerved, ſhe was now Indicted and Condemned for <hi>High Treaſon,</hi> for that ſhe had Made, Coin'd and Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terfeited twelve pieces of <hi>Copper, Tin,</hi> and other Metals, in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the likeneſs of Shillings, commonly called Queen <hi>E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lizabeths</hi> Shillings, and twelve other pieces of like Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terfeit Metal called Queen <hi>Elizabeths</hi> Sixpences, which Fact was proved againſt her, by two Women, who had often ſeen her make the ſaid counterfeit Mony, by melting <hi>Pen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, Copper,</hi> and the like, to a pound weight at a time, and pouring the ſame into Molds of Wood, which faſhi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oned it like the Shillings and Sixpences before mention<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed. They alſo confeſſed they had put off much of that counterfeit mony for her, and ſeveral pieces were produ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced in Court, upon which Evidence, ſhe was found Guil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of <hi>High Treaſon.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Having thus given the Reader an Account of the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral heinous crimes for which theſe Malefactors were con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demned I ſhall now proceed to ſpeak of the Behaviour of each perſon under ſo great a Tryal, and how they ſpent thoſe precious Minutes which formerly were often tedious to them, but now grown ſo valuable, that no good Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtian, but would part with all the Pleaſures and Riches of the World to redeem his miſpent time, or gain ſome few hours to pray to God for Mercy upon his Soul, which be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore he had ſo often ſlighted. After their Return to Priſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on. <hi>Charles Cloſe,</hi> tho before he ſeemed ſo ſteel'd in wick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>edneſs and hardned in iniquity, that neither the danger of his Life, or the Eternal Ship-wrack <hi>of</hi> his Soul, affect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed him with any <hi>ſerious</hi> conſideration, yet coming into the condemned hole, he gave a great Sigh, &amp; by ſome pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vate Ejaculations, diſcovered his heart was not ſo Obdu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate and impenetrable, as to be altogether unconcerned at his preſent condition. This happy change was ſoon taken notice of, by that Vigilant and Worthy Perſon Mr. <hi>Ordinary,</hi> who took all Opportunities to improve the leaſt
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:43825:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 3 -->ſpark of Penitence or Contrition, to a true ſence of that miſerable State he was in, a Confeſſion of thoſe manifold and grievous Crimes he had been Guilty of, and an abſolute Reſignation of himſelf to the Will of God, and the puniſhment of thoſe Laws he had ſo often Tranſgreſſed.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Bernard Trevers,</hi> and <hi>Hugh Kelly,</hi> as they had been his <hi>former</hi> Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panions in ſin and wickedneſs, ſo now do they ſhare with him in his preſent miſeries and diſtreſs: They now <hi>afreſh Confeſſed</hi> with Sor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row that Guilt they had Publickly owned at their Tryals, and as perſons whoſe Education was always looſe, and either encouraged by the Vitious Examples <hi>of</hi> others, or prompted by the pravity <hi>of</hi> their own Wills and Affections, or both; have been <hi>often</hi> Guilty of breaking the <hi>Sabbath,</hi> and ſpending the <hi>Lords Day</hi> in purſuit <hi>of</hi> Worldly buſineſs as too many do, or elſe in <hi>gratifying</hi> the Luſts <hi>of</hi> the Fleſh, <hi>unlawful</hi> Pleaſures or more wicked Deboches.</p>
            <p>On <hi>Sunday</hi> they were at Chappel, both Morning and Afternoon, &amp; behaved themſelves with that Reverence and Attention, as became perſons who were ſo ſuddenly to give an Account <hi>of</hi> every idle Thought or ſinful Glance, as they had ſo lately <hi>of</hi> their wicked Acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons. The worthy Preacher, like a true Phyſician <hi>of</hi> ſouls firſt apply<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Corroſives to make them ſenſible <hi>of</hi> themſelves, and that wretch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed State they were plunged into by that <hi>ſinful</hi> Courſe <hi>of Life</hi> they had ſo long Rioted in, he Terrified them with Gods Judgment on impeniten<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſinners, the Eternal Damnation of ſoul and body, if they did not now, while it is <hi>Called to Day,</hi> repent and turn to the living God. But on the other hand, he mercifully poured <hi>Oyle</hi> into their wounded Conſciences; and as none ought to Preſume on, ſo not to diſpair of the Mercies of Everlaſting Goodneſs.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Katherine Smith,</hi> and <hi>Mary Corbet,</hi> tho they had been both. No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torious Offenders, yet by their humble and ſubmiſſive Behaviour, ſeemed truly Penitent, and I hope the great Labors of thoſe wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thy Divines who viſited them, wrought them into a ſincere Repen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance, and that ſweetneſs of Temper, as a good Chriſtian would re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyce to die in.</p>
            <p>At <hi>ten</hi> of the clock they were put Into Carts; And <hi>Mary Corbet</hi> drawn on a <hi>Sledge</hi> to <hi>Tyburn,</hi> where ſhe was burned and the reſt <hi>Hanged.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON</hi> Printed by <hi>E. Mallet,</hi> 1684.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:43825:3"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 3 -->
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
